<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>foss on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/tags/foss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in foss on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/tags/foss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Gentoo – The Efficient Way</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/how-to-install-gentoo-the-efficient-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/how-to-install-gentoo-the-efficient-way/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So you finally moved from the beginner distributions and you know want to install truly the best operating system of all time; Gentoo Linux. Contrary to popular belief, installing this operating system is not difficult in the slightest but it is certainly time consuming. Usually it will take around five hours to install. This might deter you, but remember that this operating system will actually save you time in the long run. Not only is it faster than other operating systems, it also makes the user more intelligent, leading to efficient computer usage. No current Gentoo user regrets spending five hours installing the operating system to save many more hours in total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Pay Attention to Your Choice of Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/why-you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/why-you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What I have noticed about many subjects in life is that many people just want to be sheep. Notice how I said &amp;ldquo;want to be sheep&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;are sheep.&amp;rdquo; That is because my emphasis is on the fact that people are choosing to be ignorant. This is true in many cases, especially in politics and computing. In this post, I will be focusing on computing. I want to clarify by saying that I think there is nothing wrong with being ignorant, but it is wrong to be willfully ignorant.
I remember a couple of years ago I was a very different person than I am today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
