<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>freedom on Amarakon</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/tags/freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in freedom on Amarakon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/tags/freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ThinkPad Laptops are Timeless Machines</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/thinkpad-laptops-are-timeless-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/thinkpad-laptops-are-timeless-machines/</guid>
      <description>It is important to favor timeless computers over timed ones. Timed computers are designed to last only a short period of time; maybe a year or so. This is because they are designed to be not only fragile but also difficult to repair. This cruel combination manifests a consumerist mindset into most people. Timeless computers are designed to last as long as possible. They are always durable and reliable, not just the hardware but also the software.
Aspects of a Timed Computer Timed computers usually take the form of Macbooks and Surfaces. Macbooks are thin, light, and sleek. But they are built for an extremely restrictive, oppressive ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Spending Too Much Money on Technology</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/stop-spending-too-much-money-on-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/stop-spending-too-much-money-on-technology/</guid>
      <description>Many people feel the need to spend a lot of money on technology. They think that because technology is complex and vast, they should buy from the most expensive brands. I think that the opposite is true. Because technology is complex and vast, we should buy cheap but great tech products. Most importantly, we should buy technology that we actually understand. Ultra-complex technology takes advantage of everyone who uses it because no one can understand it. This is why we should only use technology that is simple and easy to understand. You can get by spending one quarter of what most people spend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson is a Brave Political Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Jordan Peterson is a Canadian clinical psychologist that is now known for his counter-narrative political views. He became famous after standing up against Bill C-16 which forces compelled speech. He is also mainly known for criticizing the radical left. He is often described as conservative by the right. However, just because he criticizes left-wing extremists, does not mean he is a conservative He said in an interview that he’s “no right-winger.”
  Bill C-16 Bill C-16 is a bill passed by the Parliament of Canada titled An Act to amend the Canadian Human Rights Act and the Criminal Code. It states that “gender identity and expression” are prohibited grounds of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
