<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>politics on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transgender Ideology is False, Self-Destructive, and Immoral</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/transgender-ideology-is-immoral-self-destructive-and-false/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/transgender-ideology-is-immoral-self-destructive-and-false/</guid>
      <description>You cannot change the reality of who you are. You cannot change your race, sex, age because those are immutable properties. Most people in society understand and accept this fact. But the left has created terms called “gender” and “transgender” to get around this. They know believe it is possible to change one’s sex, but they relabeled it as “gender.” They argue that sex is biological while gender is a social construct. Well, if sex is the biological truth and gender is a made-up, incorrect social construct, why should not we be truthful and get rid of the made-up, incorrect social construct?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson is a Brave Political Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Jordan Peterson is a Canadian clinical psychologist that is now known for his counter-narrative political views. He became famous after standing up against Bill C-16 which forces compelled speech. He is also mainly known for criticizing the radical left. He is often described as conservative by the right. However, just because he criticizes left-wing extremists, does not mean he is a conservative He said in an interview that he’s “no right-winger.”
  Bill C-16 Bill C-16 is a bill passed by the Parliament of Canada titled An Act to amend the Canadian Human Rights Act and the Criminal Code. It states that “gender identity and expression” are prohibited grounds of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abortion, Capital Punishment, and Euthanasia – When is Killing Acceptable</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</guid>
      <description>Conservatives and liberals strongly disagree on when killing another human being should be considered acceptable. They both agree that killing is justified in self-defense, but the agreements end there. Conservatives usually think that abortion and euthanasia are wrong while capital punishment (the death penalty) is just. They argue that killing an innocent and defenseless person (abortion and euthanasia) is always wrong while killing soulless criminals (the death penalty) is just. On the other hand, liberals think that abortion and euthanasia are sometimes justifiable while the death penalty is unjust. They argue that it is a woman’s right to choose, we should end the suffering of ill people, and that the death penalty is too harsh and cruel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
