<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Amarakon’s Website</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Amarakon’s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amarlay – Amarakon’s overlay</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amarlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amarlay/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/amarlay
Unlike AmaRYAML, Amarlay has a great name. It is a Gentoo overlay that includes dozens of unique packages, most of them not found in any other repository. Obviously, this will only be useful to Gentoo users. The best packages it includes are Zsh plugins, nerd-fonts-inconsolata, cfetch, and many Neovim plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AmaRYAML – Amarakon’s YAML</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amaryaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amaryaml/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/amaryaml
It has a terrible name but this is basically a collection of R Markdown templates. There are currently five templates available in the amaryaml package:
  Book
  Eisvogel
This is basically a simple document template. It is much better than the default pandoc template.
  GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cfetch</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/cfetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/cfetch/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/cfetch
Cfetch is a suckless-like command-line system information tool. It displays information about your operating system, kernel, packages, and more along with ASCII art of your operating system in an elegant way. The purpose of Cfetch is to quickly get information about everything quickly instead of using one different program for getting each piece of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFM – dmenu File Manager</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/dfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/dfm/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/dfm
The dmenu file manager is the best and fastest way to manage files! It is even faster than using the terminal, but has the perks of a graphical user interface. Therefore, it has the best of both worlds. You can use it to quickly open files in literally around one second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFrec – FFmpeg Record</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/ffrec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/ffrec/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/ffrec
It is annoying when the command-line option is too minimalist while the graphical option is too bloated. FFrec uses FFmpeg to record but makes it less of a hassle. It makes it just as easy to record with FFmpeg as it is with OBS. Actually, it is even easier. No setup is required because the defaults are already fantastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagickShot – ImageMagick Screenshot</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/magickshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/magickshot/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/magickshot
MagickShot is a program I created because I am surprised it does not exist yet. It is a screenshot utility, but there are many screenshot utilities. However, none of them do everything I want them to do:
 screenshot with mouse selection sceenshot a specified window screenshot a specified monitor screenshot the entire display  Most of them only support the first and last options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Sensible AutoComp</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/vim-sensible-autocomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/vim-sensible-autocomp/</guid>
      <description>  Introduction  https://github.com/amarakon/vim-sensible-autocomp
This is yet another auto-completion plugin for Vim. At this point, there are probably hundreds. So I will explain what makes mine stand out from the rest. The main reason I wrote this plugin is that I wanted an auto-completion plugin written purely in Vim script or Lua.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
