<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LibreWolf is Currently the Best Web Browser</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/librewolf-is-currently-the-best-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/librewolf-is-currently-the-best-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Qualifications In order for me to consider them good, web browsers must
  not send analytics. It should not make analytics either. I do not want to hear about how it maintains the software’s survival. I genuinely do not care. I do not want “bug reports.”
  have no home pages. Seriously, I do not want my browser to start on Google. The address bar is there for a reason. Good luck to people who are too stupid to know how to use it.
  respect users’ privacy. Web browsers must minimize telemetry as much as possible. Sometimes, telemetry is necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Disallow Your Kid to Have a Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/should-you-disallow-your-kid-to-have-a-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/should-you-disallow-your-kid-to-have-a-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>There is sadly too little debate about if you should disallow your kid to have a smartphone. This is an important discussion. There are good arguments for and against it. But most people just let their kids do whatever without thinking through it deeply. This is dangerous and careless behavior. You should heavily regulate what your kids are able to do to protect them, as a parent always should. There should be no exceptions for smartphones.
I saw a post on Quora titled My almost 16-year-old daughter wants a smartphone. How do I get her to stop bugging me about it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transgender Ideology is False, Self-Destructive, and Immoral</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/transgender-ideology-is-immoral-self-destructive-and-false/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/transgender-ideology-is-immoral-self-destructive-and-false/</guid>
      <description>You cannot change the reality of who you are. You cannot change your race, sex, age because those are immutable properties. Most people in society understand and accept this fact. But the left has created terms called “gender” and “transgender” to get around this. They know believe it is possible to change one’s sex, but they relabeled it as “gender.” They argue that sex is biological while gender is a social construct. Well, if sex is the biological truth and gender is a made-up, incorrect social construct, why should not we be truthful and get rid of the made-up, incorrect social construct?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson is a Brave Political Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Jordan Peterson is a Canadian clinical psychologist that is now known for his counter-narrative political views. He became famous after standing up against Bill C-16 which forces compelled speech. He is also mainly known for criticizing the radical left. He is often described as conservative by the right. However, just because he criticizes left-wing extremists, does not mean he is a conservative He said in an interview that he’s “no right-winger.”
  Bill C-16 Bill C-16 is a bill passed by the Parliament of Canada titled An Act to amend the Canadian Human Rights Act and the Criminal Code. It states that “gender identity and expression” are prohibited grounds of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing the Best Markup Languages for Making PDF Documents</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/comparing-the-best-markup-languages-for-making-pdf-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/comparing-the-best-markup-languages-for-making-pdf-documents/</guid>
      <description>PDF is rightfully the standard output format for documents. All word processors can output to PDF, but it is difficult to convert PDF to files word processors can edit. Most people use “what you see is what you get” word processors like Microsoft Word, Google Docs, or LibreOffice Writer. This type of word processor is convenient but it is also limited and unprofessional. It is easier to get into, but it is harder to use in the long run. This is the problem with all “what you see is what you get” programs: they do not follow the “separation of content and presentation” design principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abortion, Capital Punishment, and Euthanasia – When is Killing Acceptable</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</guid>
      <description>Conservatives and liberals strongly disagree on when killing another human being should be considered acceptable. They both agree that killing is justified in self-defense, but the agreements end there. Conservatives usually think that abortion and euthanasia are wrong while capital punishment (the death penalty) is just. They argue that killing an innocent and defenseless person (abortion and euthanasia) is always wrong while killing soulless criminals (the death penalty) is just. On the other hand, liberals think that abortion and euthanasia are sometimes justifiable while the death penalty is unjust. They argue that it is a woman’s right to choose, we should end the suffering of ill people, and that the death penalty is too harsh and cruel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Prefer Command-Line Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/you-should-prefer-command-line-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/you-should-prefer-command-line-software/</guid>
      <description>There are many benefits of preferring command-line software over graphical software. Graphical User Interfaces generally promote lazy thinking. Command-line interfaces generally promote critical thinking. I think it is unfortunate that most people have not even heard of command-line software. Whenever I would be doing my work in school by running commands, most people who pass by would assume that I am coding. This is obviously because they have not used command-line programs, so their view of a dark terminal window and fast typing of commands they do not understand leads them to this conclusion. That then leads them to the conclusion that anything other than a modern graphical “app” is too difficult for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming is Invaluable for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/programming-is-invaluable-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/programming-is-invaluable-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Most people view programming as something that only a specific type of people are able to do and should do. This specific type of person is portrayed as a genius; smarter than everyone else. This means that they think most normal people are unable to learn programming because they are not smart enough. But since they do not want to learn it themselves, they make the excuse that it is not important for them. It does not require smartness to learn programming, it only requires time, desire, and effort.
Time A common excuse for dozens of things outside of programming is “I don’t have enough time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux Should be Approved by the Free Software Foundation</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/gentoo-linux-should-be-approved-by-the-free-software-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/gentoo-linux-should-be-approved-by-the-free-software-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Gentoo Linux is a 100% free operating system. All of its source code is publicly available on GitHub, meaning that it’s open-source. It is licensed under a free license: GNU General Public License (Version 2). It does not include any preinstalled proprietary software. Its package manager, Portage, blocks proprietary software against the user’s will by default. All of these reasons prove that is a completely free operating system that is against the use of proprietary software, so it should be in the Free Software Foundation’s (FSF) list of free Linux distributions.
Free System Distribution Guidelines (GNU, 2022b) The GNU free system distribution guidelines (GNU FSDG) is an article supported by the FSF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux: The Best Operating System Ever Made</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/gentoo-linux-the-best-operating-system-ever-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/gentoo-linux-the-best-operating-system-ever-made/</guid>
      <description>In my previous blog post titled How to Install Gentoo – The Efficient Way, I said that Gentoo Linux is “truly the best operating system of all time” (Al-Zubaidi, 2022). I stand by that statement and there are many reasons as to why I think it is. The top three currently most popular operating systems are Windows 10, macOS, and Chrome OS. You may or may not have heard of Linux.
Figure 1: Operating system market share  Statcounter (2022)
Technically, Linux is not an operating in and of itself, rather it is the core of the operating system and each distribution should provide all the additional programs required for that distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Gentoo Linux – The Efficient Way</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/how-to-install-gentoo-linux-the-efficient-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/how-to-install-gentoo-linux-the-efficient-way/</guid>
      <description>So you finally moved from the beginner distributions and you know want to install truly the best operating system of all time; Gentoo Linux. Contrary to popular belief, installing this operating system is not difficult in the slightest but it is certainly time consuming. Usually it will take around five hours to install. This might deter you, but remember that this operating system will actually save you time in the long run. Not only is it faster than other operating systems, it also makes the user more intelligent, leading to efficient computer usage. No current Gentoo user regrets spending five hours installing the operating system to save many more hours in total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education Wants to Dumb Down Technology</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</guid>
      <description>I am a high school student who happens to be genuinely interested in technology. Specifically, I am interested in operating systems, programming, and free software philosophy. I have a good understanding of what makes a good piece of technology and what makes a bad piece of technology. One of the most important factors in this distinction is the effort it requires to use it. If a piece of technology is extremely complicated but effortless to use (i.e., dumbed down), then it is generally bad. If a piece of technology is minimalist but requires genuine effort to use (e.g., C, LaTeX, flip-phones), then it is generally good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Amar Al-Zubaidi; I am an Iraqi Canadian high school student. I am interested in many things:
 freedom free software philosophy minimalism GNU/Linux  Gentoo Arch   programming  C R shell   markup  R Markdown LaTeX    Projects On my GitHub page is where I have all my projects. These are some of my best projects:
 Cfetch: minimal and elegent fetch program FFRec: script to record easily using FFmpeg PAVol-Cli: easily control PulseAudio volume from the command-line MagickShot: minimal screenshot utility using ImageMagick Mstatus: minimal status program for DWM, preconfigured out of the box  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Pay Attention to Your Choice of Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</guid>
      <description>What I have noticed about many subjects in life is that many people just want to be sheep. Notice how I said &amp;ldquo;want to be sheep&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;are sheep.&amp;rdquo; That is because my emphasis is on the fact that people are choosing to be ignorant. This is true in many cases, especially in politics and computing. In this post, I will be focusing on computing. I want to clarify by saying that I think there is nothing wrong with being ignorant, but it is wrong to be willfully ignorant.
I remember a couple of years ago I was a very different person than I am today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
