<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amarakon</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amarakon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20 Best (Neo)Vim Plugins</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/20-best-neo-vim-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/20-best-neo-vim-plugins/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Vim is a text editor that is great on its own but is heavily improved by various plugins. The vast majority of the plugins in this article will not be language-specific, so they will apply whether you are coding in C or just writing a random text file. I do indeed use Neovim and not Vim, but there is only one plugin in this list that is Neovim-specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cfetch</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/cfetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/cfetch/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/cfetch
Cfetch is a suckless-like command-line system information tool. It displays information about your operating system, kernel, packages, and more along with ASCII art of your operating system in an elegant way. The purpose of Cfetch is to quickly get information about everything quickly instead of using one different program for getting each piece of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software and Hardware I Use and Endorse</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/programs/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of the most important software and hardware I use. It may include programs that I have developed myself (see my projects page).
What Makes a Good Program I do not endorse the use of proprietary software because it is immoral and bad. I use software that is minimal, extensible, and fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amarlay – Amarakon’s overlay</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amarlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amarlay/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/amarlay
Unlike AmaRYAML, Amarlay has a great name. It is a Gentoo overlay that includes dozens of unique packages, most of them not found in any other repository. Obviously, this will only be useful to Gentoo users. The best packages it includes are Zsh plugins, nerd-fonts-inconsolata, cfetch, and many Neovim plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AmaRYAML – Amarakon’s YAML</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amaryaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/amaryaml/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/amaryaml
It has a terrible name but this is basically a collection of R Markdown templates. There are currently five templates available in the amaryaml package:
  Book
  Eisvogel
This is basically a simple document template. It is much better than the default pandoc template.
  GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFM – dmenu File Manager</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/dfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/dfm/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/dfm
The dmenu file manager is the best and fastest way to manage files! It is even faster than using the terminal, but has the perks of a graphical user interface. Therefore, it has the best of both worlds. You can use it to quickly open files in literally around one second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFrec – FFmpeg Record</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/ffrec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/ffrec/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/ffrec
It is annoying when the command-line option is too minimalist while the graphical option is too bloated. FFrec uses FFmpeg to record but makes it less of a hassle. It makes it just as easy to record with FFmpeg as it is with OBS. Actually, it is even easier. No setup is required because the defaults are already fantastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MagickShot – ImageMagick Screenshot</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/magickshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/projects/magickshot/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/amarakon/magickshot
MagickShot is a program I created because I am surprised it does not exist yet. It is a screenshot utility, but there are many screenshot utilities. However, none of them do everything I want them to do:
 screenshot with mouse selection sceenshot a specified window screenshot a specified monitor screenshot the entire display  Most of them only support the first and last options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in many things:
 freedom free software philosophy minimalism GNU/Linux  Gentoo Arch   programming  C R shell   markup  R Markdown LaTeX    Projects On my GitHub page is where I have all my projects. These are some of my best projects:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Thoroughly Enjoy Harvard’s CS50 Online Course</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/i-thoroughly-enjoy-harvards-cs50-online-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/i-thoroughly-enjoy-harvards-cs50-online-course/</guid>
      <description>Recall from my second article on this website that I did not like my school&amp;rsquo;s computer science club. I listed several reasons for it, and I will briefly summarize them here.
 The teacher taught in a traditional way rather than what I expected. Only the Python programming language is taught.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ditch the Mouse, Return to the Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/ditch-the-mouse-return-to-the-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/ditch-the-mouse-return-to-the-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>I always support minimizing the amount of money you spend on technology. I have made that crystal clear. There are many things that people are spending way too much money on. But there are also many things that people are buying that they do not even need. An example of this is the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ThinkPad Laptops are Timeless Machines</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/thinkpad-laptops-are-timeless-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/thinkpad-laptops-are-timeless-machines/</guid>
      <description>It is important to favor timeless computers over timed ones. Timed computers are designed to last only a short period of time; maybe a year or so. This is because they are designed to be not only fragile but also difficult to repair. This cruel combination manifests a consumerist mindset into most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Spending Too Much Money on Technology</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/stop-spending-too-much-money-on-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/stop-spending-too-much-money-on-technology/</guid>
      <description>Many people feel the need to spend a lot of money on technology. They think that because technology is complex and vast, they should buy from the most expensive brands. I think that the opposite is true. Because technology is complex and vast, we should buy cheap but great tech products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibreWolf is Currently the Best Web Browser</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/librewolf-is-currently-the-best-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/librewolf-is-currently-the-best-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>Qualifications In order for me to consider them good, web browsers must
  not send analytics. It should not make analytics either. I do not want to hear about how it maintains the software’s survival. I genuinely do not care. I do not want “bug reports.”
  have no home pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Disallow Your Kid to Have a Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/should-you-disallow-your-kid-to-have-a-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/should-you-disallow-your-kid-to-have-a-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>There is sadly too little debate about if you should disallow your kid to have a smartphone. This is an important discussion. There are good arguments for and against it. But most people just let their kids do whatever without thinking through it deeply. This is dangerous and careless behavior. You should heavily regulate what your kids are able to do to protect them, as a parent always should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transgender Ideology is False, Self-Destructive, and Immoral</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/transgender-ideology-is-false-self-destructive-and-immoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/transgender-ideology-is-false-self-destructive-and-immoral/</guid>
      <description>You cannot change the reality of who you are. You cannot change your race, sex, age because those are immutable properties. Most people in society understand and accept this fact. But the left has created terms called “gender” and “transgender” to get around this. They know believe it is possible to change one’s sex, but they relabeled it as “gender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson is a Brave Political Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/jordan-peterson-is-a-brave-political-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Jordan Peterson is a Canadian clinical psychologist that is now known for his counter-narrative political views. He became famous after standing up against Bill C-16 which forces compelled speech. He is also mainly known for criticizing the radical left. He is often described as conservative by the right. However, just because he criticizes left-wing extremists, does not mean he is a conservative He said in an interview that he’s “no right-winger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing the Best Markup Languages for Making PDF Documents</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/comparing-the-best-markup-languages-for-making-pdf-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/comparing-the-best-markup-languages-for-making-pdf-documents/</guid>
      <description>PDF is rightfully the standard output format for documents. All word processors can output to PDF, but it is difficult to convert PDF to files word processors can edit. Most people use “what you see is what you get” word processors like Microsoft Word, Google Docs, or LibreOffice Writer. This type of word processor is convenient but it is also limited and unprofessional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abortion, Capital Punishment, and Euthanasia – When is Killing Acceptable</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/abortion-capital-punishment-and-euthanasia-when-is-killing-acceptable/</guid>
      <description>Conservatives and liberals strongly disagree on when killing another human being should be considered acceptable. They both agree that killing is justified in self-defense, but the agreements end there. Conservatives usually think that abortion and euthanasia are wrong while capital punishment (the death penalty) is just. They argue that killing an innocent and defenseless person (abortion and euthanasia) is always wrong while killing soulless criminals (the death penalty) is just.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Prefer Command-Line Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/you-should-prefer-command-line-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/you-should-prefer-command-line-software/</guid>
      <description>There are many benefits of preferring command-line software over graphical software. Graphical User Interfaces generally promote lazy thinking. Command-line interfaces generally promote critical thinking. I think it is unfortunate that most people have not even heard of command-line software. Whenever I would be doing my work in school by running commands, most people who pass by would assume that I am coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming is Invaluable for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/programming-is-invaluable-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/programming-is-invaluable-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Most people view programming as something that only a specific type of people are able to do and should do. This specific type of person is portrayed as a genius; smarter than everyone else. This means that they think most normal people are unable to learn programming because they are not smart enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux Should be Approved by the Free Software Foundation</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/gentoo-linux-should-be-approved-by-the-free-software-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/gentoo-linux-should-be-approved-by-the-free-software-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Gentoo Linux is a 100% free operating system. All of its source code is publicly available on GitHub, meaning that it’s open-source. It is licensed under a free license: GNU General Public License (Version 2). It does not include any preinstalled proprietary software. Its package manager, Portage, blocks proprietary software against the user’s will by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo Linux: The Best Operating System Ever Made</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/gentoo-linux-the-best-operating-system-ever-made/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/gentoo-linux-the-best-operating-system-ever-made/</guid>
      <description>In my previous blog post titled How to Install Gentoo – The Efficient Way, I said that Gentoo Linux is “truly the best operating system of all time” (Al-Zubaidi, 2022). I stand by that statement and there are many reasons as to why I think it is. The top three currently most popular operating systems are Windows 10, macOS, and Chrome OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Gentoo Linux – The Efficient Way</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/how-to-install-gentoo-linux-the-efficient-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/how-to-install-gentoo-linux-the-efficient-way/</guid>
      <description>So you finally moved from the beginner distributions and you know want to install truly the best operating system of all time; Gentoo Linux. Contrary to popular belief, installing this operating system is not difficult in the slightest but it is certainly time consuming. Usually it will take around five hours to install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education Wants to Dumb Down Technology</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</guid>
      <description>I am a high school student who happens to be genuinely interested in technology. Specifically, I am interested in operating systems, programming, and free software philosophy. I have a good understanding of what makes a good piece of technology and what makes a bad piece of technology. One of the most important factors in this distinction is the effort it requires to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Pay Attention to Your Choice of Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/articles/you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</guid>
      <description>What I have noticed about many subjects in life is that many people just want to be sheep. Notice how I said &amp;ldquo;want to be sheep&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;are sheep.&amp;rdquo; That is because my emphasis is on the fact that people are choosing to be ignorant. This is true in many cases, especially in politics and computing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
