<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</title>
    <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amar Al-Zubaidi’s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Education Wants to Dumb Down Technology</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/education-wants-to-dumb-down-technology/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I am a high school student who happens to be genuinely interested in technology. Specifically, I am interested in operating systems, programming, and free software philosophy. I have a good understanding of what makes a good piece of technology and what makes a bad piece of technology. One of the most important factors in this distinction is the effort it requires to use it. If a piece of technology is extremely complicated but easy to use (i.e., dumbed down), then it is generally bad. If a piece of technology is minimalist but requires genuine effort to use (e.g., C, LaTeX, flip phones), then it is generally good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Amar Al-Zubaidi; I am an Iraqi Canadian high school student. I am interested in many things:
 freedom free software philosophy minimalism GNU/Linux  Gentoo Arch   programming  C R shell   markup  R Markdown LaTeX    Projects On my GitHub page is where I have all my projects. These are some of my best projects:
 Cfetch: minimal and elegent fetch program FFRec: script to record easily using FFmpeg PAVol-Cli: easily control PulseAudio volume from the command-line MagickShot: minimal screenshot utility using ImageMagick Mstatus: minimal status program for DWM, preconfigured out of the box  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Should Pay Attention to Your Choice of Software</title>
      <link>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/why-you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amarakon.github.io/amarakon.com/blog/why-you-should-pay-attention-to-your-choice-of-software/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What I have noticed about many subjects in life is that many people just want to be sheep. Notice how I said &amp;ldquo;want to be sheep&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;are sheep.&amp;rdquo; That is because my emphasis is on the fact that people are choosing to be ignorant. This is true in many cases, especially in politics and computing. In this post, I will be focusing on computing. I want to clarify by saying that I think there is nothing wrong with being ignorant, but it is wrong to be willfully ignorant.
I remember a couple of years ago I was a very different person than I am today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
